Emilia-sama and Natsuki Subaru-sama,
I would gladly host you two at
my home for as long as you need.
We appreciate that,
but we do want to get the
villagers back home.
We'll come back after we take them all home
and talk to her sponsor, Roswaal.
Very well.
When you do, I hope I can finally
repay my great debt to you.
It's not that big a deal.
You helped us out, too.
We even got a reward. Right, Patrasche?
Ow!
Are you all right, Subaru?
Those scales hurt more than I expected!
Now I know how a daikon radish
feels when it's being grated!
Subaru-kyun, I've secured Rem-chan.
Be sure to keep her still!
Okay.
You'll need your rest when you
get back to the mansion, too.
Me?
You've been working your gate overtime
since you were going up against Sloth.
I did clean up all the toxins in your gate,
but you need to let it rest for two months.
Two months, huh?
Well, surely all this crazy stuff
can't keep happening for that long...
Wait, did I just set a flag?!
All right, it's time for you to get going.
Go on, Crusch-sama.
Give them a few parting words.
Emilia-sama, I wish you good health.
I look forward to seeing you again very soon.
You, too, Crusch-san. Please be well.
Next time, I won't just be the
one who always needs saving.
I'll become someone who can help others.
Natsuki Subaru-sama,
I wish you all the best in the future, too.
I know we will meet again.
Right, then...
You know, Subaru, you always sit beside
me as if it's the obvious choice.
Oh, is there something weird about that?
No. I felt a little uncomfortable at first,
but now it feels strange if
you don't, so it's fine.
My painstaking efforts have
finally been rewarded!
I'm so moved!
You're teasing me again.
I know you're still worried about Rem.
There's no need for you to hide that.
She's important to you, isn't she?
She is! Super important!
As important to me as you are!
You're being very selfish.
Are you aware of that?
Sure, I am.
Frankly, I feel like such scum,
I wish I could die.
But it's the absolute truth.
Subaru...
Did you just say my name?
No, I didn't!
Wait, have you been there all this time?
Of course I've been here!
Why do you think I decided
to work with you?!
I'm just kidding.
You want to negotiate with Roswaal in person.
I haven't forgotten that.
I'm begging you! My whole
life is riding on this!
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
Time to say goodbye to you for now.
Oh, wai—
I'm sure you'll find a way to get her back.
Emilia-tan...
Also, I think you and I
are the same in the sense
that we act for our own selfish reasons.
I realize that I'm participating in the
royal selection for selfish reasons, too.
Selfish?
I'm sorry... I can't explain it very well.
I don't want to hide anything from you,
but I'm not sure how to put it into words.
We can talk everything out
after we join up with Roswaal.
He might know something about
what happened to Rem, too!
Right.
You two, we'll be reaching
our destination soon!
No one's here.
No one around here, either.
What? Why?
So Ram and the others haven't
returned from the Sanctuary?
Seems that way.
By the way, Emilia-tan, do you
know where the Sanctuary is?
Huh? I thought you knew where it was.
Huh?
I know I'm late in asking,
but what kind of place is
the Sanctuary, anyway?
I'm not sure, either.
Roswaal only said it was like
a secret base... and...
And?
Nothing, never mind.
I'm sorry. I should have asked.
No, no! Even if we were in
a hurry to get to safety,
I'm the one who was way too careless!
We'll just have to head to the mansion for now.
Maybe we'll find some clues there.
Otto, come with us!
What? To the mansion?
Don't be so scared after
we've come this far.
Take the carriage and the ground
dragons around back, okay?
All right...
We're back, Rem.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Come to think of it, I don't remember
locking the door when we left.
You think we got robbed?
Beatrice stayed here, so I
don't think we need to worry.
Maybe she'll come get the
door for us if we knock.
She might come flying through
it, looking for Puck.
That's true.
Puck? Puck?
Huh? He's not responding.
Maybe he's asleep.
How about in here?
Yes, one moment, please.
Welcome home, Emilia-sama.
I have awaited your return.
Frederica?
Yes, it is I, Frederi—
Those teeth are scary!
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Frederica Baumann. I was
employed here in the past.
Now that you mention it,
I was told there was another maid
who quit just before I came here...
I merely took my leave for personal reasons.
Then I returned at Ram's request,
and found the mansion empty.
Fortunately, a letter I found
in the master's office
gave me an idea as to what had happened.
A letter?
And why did Ram ask you to come back?
When I returned,
the kitchen and the trees in the
garden were in a desolate state.
It was quite awful.
That's a pretty serious reason!
It's strange, though.
Ram has always worked hard
for us while you were away,
so why, in just the past few days...
With Rem gone, Ram couldn't
handle the mansion herself,
so she asked Frederica to help?
Would you mind explaining
to me who this girl
who bears a striking resemblance to Ram is?
She's Ram's younger sister, Rem.
She's a really nice girl.
She's kind, strong, and a super-hard worker.
Even I could tell that she
and Ram were really close.
I'm sure you were a good friend to her, too.
You... probably don't remember, though, right?
Unfortunately, no.
I wonder how the master and Ram
will react when they return...
I can't even guess what Roswaal will do.
And... I don't want to
imagine how Ram will react.
Hey, Frederica, have you
heard anything from Roswaal?
Sadly, I have no way of knowing all
that goes on in the master's mind.
I believe there are only two people in
this world he trusts enough for that.
Two?
Ram and the great spirit of this
mansion's forbidden library.
Great spirit of the forbidden library?
I refer to Beatrice-sama.
Hey, Beako! Long time no see!
Now I see why the mansion
suddenly seemed so noisy.
Everyone's been worried about you.
You should apologize, even if
it has to wait until later.
Apologize? Me?
I fail to comprehend why I
must apologize, and to whom, I suppose.
I could go apologize for you, if you want.
I'll tell them you were thanking me with
tears and snot streaming down your face.
Don't make up stories!
I haven't shed tears in a
very long time, I suppose.
It never hurts to have a good
wail every once in a while.
Those words carry deep meaning,
coming from a man who bawled in
the lap of the woman he loves.
Would you just forget about that already?
Could you please get to the point, I suppose?
You weakling.
Oh, yeah...
How well do you know what
Roswaal's thinking?
Someone told me that you
know how Roswaal thinks.
Who said—
Ah.
It must have been the
half-beast girl who just came back.
There is a bit of accuracy to
what she told you, I suppose.
But my connection with Roswaal has nothing
to do with the current circumstances.
But you stayed here at the mansion by yourself,
even with no countermeasures in place.
I'm capable of protecting myself.
That's why I stayed, I suppose.
Roswaal has nothing to do with that.
That said, I don't believe he had
nothing on his mind at all, I suppose.
Hmm...
Were you and I and everyone else
just giving him too much credit,
thinking he wouldn't go up against
the Witch's Cult with no plan?
Oh, that's right.
Take a look at this.
A Gospel...
Why do you, of all people,
have one of those?!
I took it off the enemy after a battle.
It belonged to the guy in charge of the witch
cultists who surrounded the mansion.
And what became of him?
He's dead.
I killed him.
Then you've left me behind, too, I suppose...
Geuse.
Who's that?
None of your concern.
Anyway, if you killed Sloth, a Sin Archbishop,
what happened to his Witch Factor?
Witch... Factor?
You don't know what it is? You really don't?
If that's the case, then why
did you bother to kill Sloth?
And what is Roswaal...
I told you, remember?
Roswaal is at the Sanctuary!
I'm the one who wants to
know what he's thinking!
All the answers you seek lie
in the Sanctuary, I suppose.
What?
Roswaal's intentions, the meaning of the Gospel,
answers about the Witch Factor...
They're all there.
If you want them, go there.
The half-beast girl can
lead you there, I suppose.
Hang on a second! What's up with you?
Why are you suddenly willing to talk to me?
Also, why do I have to go to
the Sanctuary when you—
I will not tell you.
I have the right to refuse to tell you.
I showed you the path that
leads to your answers.
Do not expect me to indulge
you any further, I suppose!
Beako... Beatrice!
I am not a tool here for your convenience!
Wh-Why did you fly into me just
as I was leaving the bathroom?!
Why did you look like you
were about to cry again?
Excuse me! Could you please get off of—
So you really are allowed to enter
Beatrice-sama's forbidden library?
What? You thought I wouldn't be?
Yes, but Emilia-sama has told me
what a reliable person you are,
and she was quite thorough
in explaining why,
so half of me had high
hopes that you would be.
Huh?
Hey! Frederica!
What? What did you tell her?
It's not like that! I did tell her
about you, but she's exaggerating!
No, I heard what you said, too.
It made me think there must be more
to Natsuki-san than meets the eye.
Not you, too, Otto-kun!
Why wasn't I around to hear all this?!
I could never say it in front of you.
Now, Frederica, back to what you were saying!
Yes, of course. I know.
Let us talk it over so you don't
find yourself at a dead end.
Dead end? What do you mean?
Even if you were able to see Beatrice,
whether or not she'd answer your
question was another matter.
Both you and Beatrice can be
very stubborn, you know.
That description is way too cute,
but you're right.
And?
There's a lot I want to talk
to Roswaal about, too.
So I asked Frederica
to tell me where the Sanctuary is.
The half-beast girl can
lead you there, I suppose.
So you're going to tell us
where it is, Frederica?
I was no match for
Emilia-sama's persistence,
even though I have been told not to
disclose any more than necessary.
But I would like to ask
for a bit of time to prepare.
Shall we say two days?
Prepare?
Oh, that's right. We'd all be
leaving the mansion, so that's—
No, I will be staying in the mansion.
I cannot accompany you.
What? You're not going with us?
How are we supposed to get there, then?
You're rather slow on the uptake, Natsuki-san.
Oh! So Otto's gonna get us to the Sanctuary?
Because he thinks cooperating
with Emilia in any way possible
will give Roswaal, her backer,
a better impression of him?
No, er...
Otto-kun, is that true?
Emilia-sama's pure, innocent
eyes are killing me!
I'm sorry! That's exactly right!
The way you wear your ulterior motive on your
sleeve makes you all the more likable, Otto.
That's not exactly comforting,
coming from you!
I appreciate your help.
On that note, you can tell the
three of us about the Sanctuary.
Very well.
What I am about to tell you
is the undisclosed location of the Sanctuary
of Clemaldy, and how to enter it.
And there is one name you must
not forget as you travel there.
Beware of one by the name of "Garfiel."
At the Sanctuary,
he will be the one with whom you
must exercise the most care.
Rem...
We're leaving now.
I told Frederica to take good care of you.
Be good and wait here for me, okay?
You're ready?
Sure am, new recruit.
I see you're rocking the uniform already.
Right?
Did you say goodbye to Rem-san?
Yeah, something like that.
We're not planning to stay out there long,
but I wanted to see her first.
Could you take care of Rem for
me while I'm gone, Petra?
Understood, Subaru-sama!
Still, we started advertising to
hire a new maid two days ago,
and this is your first day
actually being in the mansion.
I'm impressed you found the
place without getting lost.
And I really admire your decision to
leave your parents at such a young age.
I'm twelve years old! I'm old
enough to be a working grown-up!
I mean... an adult!
You need to treat me like
an adult, too, Subaru-sama!
Get better at speaking politely and
get Frederica to fully initiate you,
and I'll think about it.
'Kay!
I mean... yes, sir!
I forgot what a pain she can be
when she's serious about hiding.
Is there really a mysterious room here?
Yeah... Beatrice.
You know her, right?
Take care of her for me, too.
You might randomly encounter her
when opening a door somewhere.
Wait, Subaru-sama! Aren't you
asking a bit much of me?
I know. Sorry.
But you're the only one I can ask.
I really am sorry.
Oh, all right!
If you insist, I'll just have to help you out!
Thanks. You're really a huge help.
Take care of the mansion for us.
And Rem, Petra, and Beatrice, too.
You can rely on me.
Take care during your travels, Emilia-sama.
And take this.
This will allow you to get past
the barrier in the forest,
and enter the Sanctuary.
From there, the ground dragons should
take you to the location I described.
So this stone is the requirement
to get through the barrier?
You have the location and the qualification.
Now you only need the
resolve and a strong will.
Frederica...
Take good care of the Sanctuary.
And do not forget what I said earlier.
Okay. We'll watch out for Garfiel.
I promise.
Um, Subaru-sama...
Would you please accept this?
Uh...
Lending a white handkerchief to a traveler,
who later returns it stained
and worn from the journey,
is an old custom performed as
a prayer for safe travels.
Oh, it's one of those things?
Okay, got it. Thanks, Petra.
I promise I'll return it.
What? What brought that reaction on?
This sudden rebellious phase is making me sad.
Now, you should hurry.
The Lost Forest of Clemaldy grows
more dangerous as night approaches.
I wish you a safe journey.
Subaru-sama!
You'd better protect the lady!
I have done exactly as Master directed.
Now everything depends on how
Emilia-sama overcomes the Sanctuary.
There is nothing we can do but pray.
Puck isn't showing up?
Yeah.
I've called out to him several times,
and I can feel the link
from our contract, but...
Has anything like this happened before?
Not very often, but there
have been a few times
when he didn't show up for a few days.
I'm counting on you to take care of Lia.
Couldn't have been...
But I do have contracts
with lesser spirits, too,
and I can also fight with them.
No matter what happens, I'll protect you!
Wow, you're so manly!
Hey!
Frederica did warn us that
something might happen.
Oh... Garfiel, right?
Yeah. Roswaal did mention a few times
that he was going to see him...
Excuse me!
We're in the forest!
The Lost Woods of Clemaldy.
A special barrier there protects the Sanctuary.
It makes outsiders lose their way,
to prevent them from getting close.
That is why they call it the "Lost Woods."
So the Sanctuary is just ahead...
Emilia-tan, are you actually nervous?
Huh? How could you tell?
I know everything about you!
At least, that's what I'd like
to say, but anyone could tell.
You're right!
I'm sorry for worrying you.
When I think that we're about
to arrive at the Sanctuary,
a village where only demihumans live...
No, I should apologize. I wasn't
thinking that far ahead.
I guess there might be more
half-elves like you there, huh?
I've never seen any half-elves
other than myself.
But just maybe, in the Sanctuary...
Don't worry. I'll—
Emilia?!
Uh... Is this...
I suddenly have a really bad feeling!
I'm borrowing this, Emilia!
Emilia!
Where... am I?
Who are you?
Those ears...
Are you an elf?
No, wait! Wait a minute!
Hey! Is anyone here?
If this is the Sanctuary,
somebody answer me!
This is...
I see.
So that is the root of your desire?
How very interesting.
Oh, did I startle you?
It has been quite a while
since I spoke with anyone,
so perhaps I was too eager.
My name is Echidna...
Or perhaps you would know me
better as the Witch of Greed?
The Next Location
If it's
to save you
I don't care
how many times
I die